Viktoria

Hanke

QA ENGINEER



Number **0176-813-85-161**

<u>Email</u> viktoriiahanke91@gmail.com

<u>City</u> **Hamburg**

<u>Linkedln</u> linkedin.com/viktorija-hanke

SUMMARY

Experienced QA Manager {Software Engineer}, IT Project Architect with 5+ years of experience in manual and automated testing, customer support and system administration. Hands-on experience with Selenium, SQL, Python, JAVA, Oracle, JavaScript. Onboarding Engineer for Stern Auto GmbH [Mercedes Benz] and a mentor for more than 8 interns.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Staatliche Handelsschule Berliner Tor

2018 - 2019 Project Management, Office Executive, Customs Development, Customer Support, Fortbildung | Staatliche Handelsschule Berliner Tor, Hamburg

· Kharkiv National University, Ukraine

2009 - 2014 Marketing and Brand Management with focus on the English language, MSc | Kharkiv National University, Ukraine

EXPERIENCE

MAR 2022 - PRESENT Quality Assurance Manager | ISS GmbH Sopra Steria

- Designed and updated more than 50 test cases based on customer defined software requirements using 15 test management tools.
- Performed manual functional, acceptance, smoke, regression, ad hoc testing on features and bug fixes of web-based applications: WinSure Insurances and Services.
- Created automation regression tests using TestComplete PL SQL
 Oracle C# and .Net
- Logged, tracked and verified resolution of software and specification defects along with documenting all phases of QA process using bug tracking system JIRA, Xray.

Tools: TestComplete, Oracle, SQL, C#, Python, .Net, AWS, Toad **Key Achievements:** got 100% positive customer feedback, found more than 5 critical bugs, supported customer with testing requirements documentation, improved internal processes.

DEC 2020 - März 2022 Manual QA | Cloud and IT
Operations Specialist | DevOps | Business Service
Peliyend AG (individuelle Gesamtlösungen rund Cloud,
SAP und IoT), Hamburg

- Provided technical support for Microsoft O365, Citrix and Cloud Environment, Business Skype, Citrix, nonSAP Applications.
- Researched and resolved customer problems to maintain and improve customer service and business processes.
- Hot-line and E-Mails Processing, capable of working under pressure. Answered up to 30 calls daily in a high volume call center environment, completing up to 40 Mails daily.
- Creating Back-ups, performing Software center Updates, reporting Bugs to JIRA and customers.
- Manual testing of CRM System, handling Tickets for Technical Support, maintaining IT plattform and Terminal Servers

Tools: SQL Server Management Studio, Terminal Server, Microsoft Azure, HP Service Manager, Exchange Admin Center, PowerShell, Active directory, Java, Python.

Number **0176-813-85-161**

<u>Email</u> viktoriiahanke91@gmail.com

<u>City</u> Hamburg

<u>Linkedln</u> linkedin.com/viktoriia-hanke **Key Achievements:** now I am working in Business Service Delivery, department, which is strongly connected to project management and system administration, started in the company on the position of 1st level technical supporter and was promoted within 7 month due to strong performance and organizational impact on a service desk, customer transition processes, technical knowledge. I am mentor for 3 interns.

NOV 2019 - DEC 2020 Technical Customer Support
Office Executive | Concell GmbH & Co. Kg
(Beratungsunternehmen im Bereich der
Mobilfunkbranche, Tochterunternehmen von Deutsche
Telekom), Reinbek

- Respond to customers' enquiries up to 25 per day relating to information, product functionality and fault calls resolving as many queries as possible on the first level technical support
- Manage the resolution process for 40 end customers relating to WLAN/LAN
- Performed manual testing of the Data System to identify potential pain points for users and loopholes
- Controlled contracts for End Users and B2B Users B2C Users.
- Collaborated with front-end developers and support teams to complete comprehensive testing.

Tools: Microsoft Office 365, HTML5, CSS3, Figma, Canva, JIRA, Microsoft Azure, Wobis, JavaScript.

Key Achievements: designed new feature for login mask with collaboration with front-end developers, found more than 5 critical bugs, got 100% positive customers feedback.

AUG 2018 - JULY 2019 Project Manager | K Line Kawasaki Kisen Group GmbH (Kunden: VW Konzern, Mercedes Konzern, BMW), Hamburg

- Worked to advance a positive supply chain and powerful logistics networks
- Confirmed purchase orders and made and documented shipping arrangements
- Accommodating export and import documentation
- Tran-shipment, as well as customer support department
- Developed projects and managed the transition and sales department.

Tools: Microsoft Office 365, Figma, Canva, JIRA, Microsoft Azure, WordPress, Teams.

Key Achievements: organised christmas event for 300+ employees.

COURSES | CERTIFICATES

- JUNE AUGUST 2022 | Front End Development | Hillel IT School Kyiv Ukraine
- JAN 2022 APRIL 2022 IT Project Management | Hillel IT School Kyiv Ukraine
- AUGUST 2021 JANUARY 2022 TestNG, Java, Jenkins, Selenium, Rest, Maven,
 Git | Hillel IT School Kyiv Ukraine
- AUGUST 10 11 Active Directory Webinar | q.beyond AG
- JUNE 2020 AUG 2020 Code for the WEB HTML5 CSS3, creating a great UI
 UX for Mobile Apps | University of Leeds Institute of Coding London
- OCTOBER 2020 INTRODUCTION TO BUSINESS MANAGEMENT |

KING'S COLLEGE LONDON

<u>Number</u>

0176-813-85-161

<u>Email</u>

viktoriiahanke91@gmail.com

<u>City</u>

Hamburg

<u>Linkedln</u>

linkedin.com/viktoriia-hanke

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JAVA
- C#
- Python
- Angular
- Test Complete
- Oracle
- Toad for Oracle
- SQL
- TestNG
- Tom Cat Apache
- Selenium
- Selenide
- REST
- Bitbucket
- Source Tree
- GIT
- AWS
- Cypress
- Active Directory
- Citrix
- JIRA
- Confluence
- Manual Testing
- Figma
- Power BI
- Microsoft 365
- Linux Majaro
- VMWare
- ASG Windows Server 2016
- Microsoft Azure

LANGUAGES

German - C1, English - C1, Russian - native